Angelica Bonilla Fominaya

(305) 833-1480, abonilla@andrew.cmu.edu, abfominaya.com

I am a student at Carnegie Mellon with an interest in Computer Science, Machine Learning (ML) and Human-Computer Interaction (HCI). I am particularly passionate about the intersection of creative fields, such as art, with software engineering and space. I am currently pursuing a minor in Neural Computation and an internship at NASA Langley Research Center.

Education

BCSA. Computer Science and Fine Arts

Minor in Neural Computation Carnegie Mellon University 2023. 3.64 GPA

Skills

Relevant Coursework

Principles of Imperative Computation; Human-AI Interaction; Interactivity & Computation; Statistics; Functional Programming; Interaction Design Overview; Matrices and Linear Transformations; Introduction to Computer Systems, Parallel Data Structures and Algorithms.

Programming/Design Skills:

Python, Java, Javascript, C, Unity, SML, C++, CSS, SQL, MATLAB, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, In-Design, HTML.

Other skills:

Leadership, Spanish (fluent), group work, communication, organization, data analysis.

Experience

Incoming Google Software Engineer Intern (May, 2022 - August, 2022)

NASA SUITS Challenge Team Lead (August, 2021 - Present)

- Led and organized team of 8 designers, artists and programmmers to participate in the NASA SUITS challenge, where we designed and built an AR application for EVA assistance.
- Wrote 10-page proposal paper outlining initial designs.
- Programmed and designed task navigation and voice user interface using MRTK and C# in Unity.

NASA Research Intern (LaRC) (August, 2021 - Present)

- Researched safety justification and ethics as it pertains to engineering decisions in autonomous vehicles, culminating in a position paper.
- Designed and built a parser for FAN (Fun Argument Notation) using ANTLR and Java.

Google STEP Intern (May, 2021 - August, 2021)

- Designed and implemented in C++ a retrieval simulator tool that estimates metrics for app-recommendation targeting ML models.
- Implemented and designed features to aggregate, slice and filter metrics and designed metrics visualizations and test data using SQL and Python.
- Completed evaluation and development process, including the writing of design documents, code reviews and a final presentation.

Human-Computer Interaction Institute RA (September, 2020 - December, 2020)

- Planned, ran and co-designed focus groups and mini game jams.
- Analyzed qualitative data and researched on counterspaces.

Hack112 Hackathon Special Category Award

- Utilized **iterative digital prototyping (Unity)** for *Counterspace Games*.

Latin American Comics Archive encoder and contributor (August, 2020 - Present)

Honors

Marjory Glassburnn Francis Award	April, 2022
FRFAF Microgrant	November, 2021
Anne Ophelia Dowden Award	May, 2021
Dean's List	Spring - Fall, 2020
RIYR Fellowship (granted by the Studio for Creative Inquiry)	May, 2020
Anne Ophelia Dowden Award	May, 2020

Scholastics Art and Writing Awards National Gold Medalist

June 2019

November 2019